Hello friends, you are watching Desi
Driver channel.  So today we will talk about
how you can become a general insurance agent.
Motor vehicle insurance
also includes health, but our main focus will be on
auto insurance.  So, we will talk about
what qualifications you need and what you know.
In this you can use
all the vehicles like car, bike, truck, pickup etc.
And we will
also talk about the margin involved in this.
So, mainly, pickup, truck, car and all the
vehicles come under this.  All the bikes arrive.
First party,
third party insurance, everything is included in it,
zero death insurance is also included in it.  It
depends on what the customer's demand is.   The
minimum qualification required for this is
10th pass.  Minimum is 10th.  That
criteria is city wise that it can include
12th as well as 10th.  But
minimum is 10th.  Anyone who has 10th
certificate is eligible for it.
Required documents remain.  One is
your 10th marksheet.  There is a PAN
card.  An Aadhar card, a cancelled
cheque and a photograph.  You have to submit all these documents
and
I will give the link of what is on which website
in the description and
I will also put a video in it while filling a form, the
commission ratio in this is
17% to 30% and it depends on how many
policies you take for how much premium.  For example, if it is up
to Rs 1 lakh,
you get 18-20% on it.  If you pay a premium of Rs 1 lakh to Rs 2 lakh,
you will be charged 15, 20, 30% tax.
So let us see
how to fill this form now.
How do you fill out your form to become an agent?
So I am showing you a sample
of SBI.  So we will go to Google and write
SBI General Insurance Agent.  So this
is coming up Become an Agent.  If you click on this,
you can apply for it here.
In this, the same thing that I told you,
what is your eligibility?  What
is the qualification?  You will get it in details.  In this you have to give
a training, there is an IDA exam,
you have to give that and there is also a 50 hour
training for it online and you
also get study material, you can do it from that also, so you
can do it as study material also, let us now fill the form,
in this you have to write your name,
write your first name, then write your
second last name, then
write your mobile number,
then you have an email ID on which all the
further details will come to your mail,
so enter that number, select your city
where you live, from
where you want to start your work.  There is
no office fee requirement in this.  You can work even without an office.
What is your profession?  Whether you are self-
employed or already in business or
in a job, please write the details.  Please write your age.
How old are you?  If
you already have an agent then say yes.
If you are not an agent then you
can select No Pay This Pay.  If you
are already connected to someone then you have to
enter the details in it.  Otherwise,
you can go to PAN lookup on IRDA website and check
whether you are already associated with any company
or not.  You
can check it there by entering your PAN number.  On this
you click on submit.  So
this form gets submitted as soon as you click on submit.
You will receive an email and a
call from any agent within a day or two.  The
relationship manager of the company will
call you and tell you what you need to do
for the further process.  So
all this detail has come.  How can you fit into this?  Let me show you
another form.
National Insurance agent is a very big
brand.  We will talk about two big brands.
We will not go into many brands.
More than 30 companies work here.
So now we will talk about National Insurance.  So let us
click on National Insurance.
What are your qualifications in this also
?  Will there be any
document requirement for you?
What should be your minimum age in this
?  All the details are written on it.
Then coming down, you select whether
you or anyone in your family is covered under
National Insurance.  If
you have it then you cannot apply for it.  If it
is no then click on no and
then click on click here below.
Then the complete form will open.  So
please zoom in and see it.  In this, you will have to fill up the details
step by step just like you had
filled up the details in the last form
and if
you submit it in the same way, then as soon as you submit it,
you will get a notification on
your mail that your form has been submitted
and you will get a call back within two-three days
and in this it
depends on you with which brands you want to
associate.  So according to me, the
best brands are SBI National,
you can join these two companies.  You
can also join ICC LBA.  You can also join Bajaj.
You
can also join United India Insurance.  You can join If Tokyo.  There are
many brands and non-brands and it
depends on which one you want to go with.
Many new companies are also coming up, so it depends on
you
which brand you want to go for.
Who you want to work with.  So if
you want to
know any details related to this, you can message me.
Thank you for watching my video.